# YOFETAHE S. HABTU

(206) 887 6266 • yofetahe@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/yofetahe-habtu/

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Full stack developer with 4+ years of professional experience on web-based application development. Proactive learner, continuously improving skills and researching leading-edge tools to ensure relevant knowledge within constantly changing IT landscape. Determined to take part on every level of development and contribute something valuable for the group or environment I am working in. Work with my colleagues collaboratively to result in unified and issue-free applications.

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, C#, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, XML, jQuery, AJAX, JSP, Node.js, Socket.io

Databases: Oracle, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Mongo DB

Frameworks: Spring, Hibernate, Angular, Entity Framework, Express.js, Flask, Django, Bootstrap, Materialize

**Tools**: Eclipse, IntelliJ, NetBeans, JDeveloper, MS Visual Studio, MYSQL Workbench

Integration: IBM Integration Bus (IIB V10), IBM MQ

Platforms: Windows, Mac OS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- I. Software Engineer, March 2015 to April 2018 | YamGet IT Solutions Plc Addis Ababa, ETH Helped build and enhance highly available, scalable, real-time and secure systems used by customers. Provide object-oriented software (OOS) design and development of web based applications for services provider companies and for diverse client base.
  - Completed six major projects, worked as a full stuck developer closely with agile development team to code, test and maintain Web based software applications.
  - Adhered to high-quality development standards while delivering solutions on-time and on-budget.
  - Facilitated customization of systems by encouraging software engineering team to adopt emerging standards for software application development architecture and tools.
  - Participated in sales presentations due to ability to translate user needs into easy-to-understand software solutions. Helped sales team on major deals generating well formatted and easy to understand system presentation.
- II. Software Engineer, April 2014 March 2015 | Apposit LLC Addis Ababa, ETH

Played a good role in the team, responded to all requests as fast as possible, abide by the plan set with the team and submit the development on time.

- Take a role in two of the major projects of the company as a full stuck developer.
- Perform debugging on the existing system, Develop new features as per end users request and test what is added
- Take part on the enhancement of previous version to new version,
- Develop new sub project on the existing platform when a new organization join the technology.

III. Software Engineer, Web Design Engineer, Junior Software Engineer, Junior Information Analyst, September 2010 – March 2014 | Ethiopian Revenues and Customs Authority – Addis Ababa, ETH

Went through several promotions, culminating on my last software engineer role through a good contribution on firm's software development activities. Provide cradle-to-grave oversight of software internal project management, design, development, documentation, testing and rollout of enterprise applications.

- Contributed software engineering expertise in the development of products through the software lifecycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.
- Excelled in rapid application development and management of technological issues for assigned projects, earning the highest customer satisfaction rating for all software solutions delivered.
- Introduced methodologies and best practices that enhanced product definition, release processes and customization of applications to user needs.
- Participate in the clearance of the data in the database and provide well formatted information for managers and external end users.

# **EDUCATION**

# Full Stack Development Certificate

Coding Dojo, Seattle USA | January – April, 2019

#### Coursework:

**Web-Fundamental** (HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS, Balsamiq) ● **Python Stack** (Python Core, Flask, Ajax, Django, MySQL, AWS) ● **MEAN Stack** (Mongo DB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js, Socket.io) ● **C# Stack** (C# core, ASP.NET, Entity Framework)

# Bachelor of Science in Management Information System

Micro-Link Information Technology College, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia | September 2005 – August 2009 Coursework:

Object-Oriented Programming (Java) • Windows Programming (VB) • Front End Programming (HTML, JS & CSS) • Database Management Systems • Software Project Management • Information Systems • Networking System Analysis & Design

# **Professional Short Term Training**

Fundamental of Java Programming • SQL • Developing Web Applications using JSF Technologies • Business Component Development With EJB Technology • IT Risk Management • ITIL